

HASAN BADRAN

SENIOR MOBILE DEVELOPER

+961 78 801759 • hasanbadran88@gmail.com • Lebanon, Beirut

PROFILE

Self taught mobile apps and game developer, my main development is Android since 1.5 year and recently diving into IOS development, $well \ experienced \ with \ dependency \ injections, RxJava, \ multithreaded \ apps, functional \ programming \ in \ JAVA, JAVA 9, MVP, MVVM, MVC$ And XML, Open-source developer published 10 Repositories including 8 Android Libraries, Developed more than 8 functioning apps and 10 Android projects.

EDUCATION

2016 -Lebanese University 2019

Computer Science

2015 -**Basilic College**

2015 Master In Mobile Maintenance

WORK EXPERIENCE

EConcepts • Android Developer

2017 - 2019

Designed and developed android apps in the field of ecommerce using Magento.

Responsible for maintaining and refactoring apps done by previous developers.

MEES • Android And Arduino Developer

2018 - 2019

Designed and developer IOT App to control home through phone and wifi with HTTP, MQTT.

Designed and developed INDUSTRY 4.0 desktop app using Java for factories.

SKILLS

Java 9 Multithreaded Apps

Swift Database Design

JavaFx С

Functional Java Python

RxJava **Reactive Programming**

MVP,MVVM,MVC,MVPVM Adobe

Dependency Injection **Jmeter Stress Testing**

Firebase **Network Protocols**

MySQL **Socket Programming**

Database Admin Agile

Corona Game Dev IoT and Arduino

E2E and P2P Apps Laravel

Microservices **REST API**

Spring Framework LUA

Docker Matlab

Espresso Framework **JavaScript**

Quantum Programming GeoFencing

Social: Github: @Badranh • Stack: @Badran • Medium: @hasanbadran88 • Youtube: @cryptobrewery



HASAN BADRAN

SENIOR MOBILE DEVELOPER

+961 78 801759 • hasanbadran88@gmail.com • Lebanon, Beirut

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

University Project ● Decentralized Voting System 2017 - 2018

Designed and developed a decentralized blockchain system for voting which is built on JAVAFX and using Blockchain Concepts (Hashing - Mining - Merkle Trees and Tokens).

University Project • Agile Moves 2018 - 2019

Developed An Agile System for teams to enhance the coordination and productivity.

Built using Laravel, HTML, CSS and JS.

University Project • Industry 4.0 2018 - 2019

Developed A desktop app and Arduino device to create a full fledged IoT system for industries to control and monitor it through the app.

The App was build using RXJAVA- JAVA - JAVAFX- Concurrent Programming-IoT-C-HTML.

University Project ◆Shop It 2018 - 2019

Developed An Android app and database for supermarkets, the Android app will replace the old cashier systems through integrating Barcode reader.

The project was developed using JAVA- SQL - MSSQL - BATCH Scripts - JDBC - Shell Scripts.

Own Project • Drive Well 2017 - 2018

Designed and developed Android app that uses google mobile vision API, it is goal to wake up sleepy drivers, the google API was used to get the eye values and created my own algorithm to decide whether the driver is sleepy or not.

Own Project • Parcel Hero 2017 - 2018

Designed and developed Android app that uses Firebase Realtime Database, MySQL and Google maps, the app goal was to provide a free reliable live tracking system with a peer to peer delivery system,.

Own Project • Crypto Pocket Guide 2017 - 2018

Designed and developed Android app that uses REST-API to get the latest news of cryptocurrencies.

Own Project • Space Blasts 2017 - 2018

Designed and developed Cross Platform game using Corona engine and LUA Scripting.

Open Source Libraries And Projects • Github MVPVM Design Pattern - Android POC + Sample App MSSQL Database Optimizer - Util Syntax View Android - Android Library Customizable Material Dialog Box - Android Library Process Button - Android Library MAC address Util - Android Library

Tutorials: E2E Chatting App, Quantum Computing Examples,RX JAVA Database, Android Coding IDE

ACHIEVMENTS

Discovered 2 bugs in LinkedIn.

Discovered security flaw in Smart Home System.

Reached top 0.2% in StackOverFlow.

Social: Github: @Badranh • Stack: @Badran • Medium: @hasanbadran88 • Youtube: @cryptobrewery